All right, so while you guys were off doing dumb things like being a rock, getting nosebleeds, or messing with ingredients, I managed to find some patterns in the dungeon's changes.
You make it sound like I wanted to turn to stone!
Yeah, give us a break.
Those three days were very productive.
Uh-huh.
When one place gets blocked, another opens up.
And that happens over and over.
The number of doors, furniture, and building types doesn't change.
The houses won't become cemeteries.
The walls move in a clockwise spiral at set intervals.
And all the statues are in a fixed position.
And then, based on other things.
I recognize this road!
I'm pretty sure that's the house where we ate the dragon.
Chill, Chuck, you're incredible!
Hey, just doing my job.
Hey, wait, isn't this road...
So she remembers it.
We got separated from Fallon here.
Only a trail of blood's been left behind.
If they notice the trail, they'll get worked up.
How am I gonna handle that?
Laios, look there!
Wait a second.
Listen, you guys!
I know there are lots of things to worry about, but for now, we should probably return to the surface?
This was where the dragon's corpse was supposed to be, wasn't it?
Yeah, but it's been cleared away with no remains.
That hole in the wall over there.
Pretty sure it's from when the red dragon fell down after we got the best of it.
It looks almost completely sealed up now.
The eye of the mage is quickly approaching.
Don't just yell all of a sudden!
But I just saw...
Huh?
Uh...
Mahana's sickness again, maybe?
Again?
Ever since I used that healing magic, I've been hallucinating and hearing things.
Hearing things?
I'm not sure if that's a symptom.
What was it you heard?
Oh, it said the eye of the mage approaches.
The eye of the mage, huh?
That must mean...
I'm hearing wings.
That small dragon.
We need to go and hide.
Hide where exactly?
Yeah, there's nowhere for us to take cover.
We've gotta run, Marcel.
Not yet.
If we need to hide...
We go in the wall!
Come on!
Hurry up, you two!
What is she?
It's another one of her magic spells?
Tell me, Marcel.
That magic you used...
What the hell was that?
Huh?
Wait, cleaners?
Excuse me?
Dungeon cleaners.
They're vital creatures to the dungeon.
Basically, they clean trash and repair places that have been destroyed.
Uh-huh.
The wall wasn't fully restored, so I assumed it hadn't hardened yet.
This part is the original wall.
And the cleaners start down here!
And the floor.
They've even reconstructed it with the wear and tear a normal road would have.
You'd never be able to tell the difference.
Huh?
What the hell are these gross little things crawling all over the ground?
Disgusting.
These are also cleaners.
Any dungeon that didn't have these little guys would fall apart immediately.
And thankfully, they're harmless.
No, they're not.
These pesky little critters are always trying to chew up my tent.
They start destroying whatever they feel is in the way.
Guess that includes your tent, Senshi.
But they're here to eat the dragon's corpse and the rubble from the blast.
They appear when the dungeon receives damage
and use their secretions to stop any further damage.
Then they proceed to eat the debris around the area.
They're not picky.
After that, they use more secretions to cover up holes they find
and restore the dungeon to its original form.
It's the same way living beings heal themselves.
To put it another way,
think of it like how our immune system removes bacteria.
Yeah, I'd rather not.
The way all that works sure feels like some type of magic.
Amazing, right?
Criminy.
What the hell's next?
A magical digestive system?
If that was really a thing,
I wonder what food a dungeon would eat.
I'm glad the blood trail wasn't there anymore.
Hey, let's continue on before another change happens.
It's the stairs! Yay!
Finally, we can get out of this place.
All right.
Now's about the time we should start doing that thing.
Yeah, good point.
Let's do that.
What the...
Oh, right.
Now I get it.
Wait, you guys meant preparing a meal?
I really don't think there are any tentacles on these stairs.
Say that sooner!
You just like wearing that, don't you?
Hell no!
We've got tons of different ingredients.
I'm having a hard time deciding what to make.
Maybe I'll use that new thing.
Cook the barley.
Is that what we picked up from the third floor?
I've been holding on to it in case we ran out of food since it keeps well.
The cockatrice meat,
the dryad fruit,
and the mandrake along with its leaves.
Chop up the depetrification herb.
Season all that and fry it.
Now, stuff some barley rice into the hollowed-out brick.
Top it with the rest and put the brick over the fire.
And then...
What is that thing?
This here's a cockatrice egg.
I'm glad I brought it along with us,
but it's pretty dang difficult to use.
Finally, add the egg sauce over top,
and it's ready.
Whoa, what is this?
This looks tasty.
If I had stayed petrified longer,
would Senshi have used me to make this?
I love this barley rice.
Go on and try stabbing the spoon into the bowl.
I took a couple bricks made by dungeon cleaners and carved them out.
Then does that mean the bowl's edible, too?
This is great.
Thanks, Senshi.
What's it taste like?
At first, it just tasted like dirt.
But now that it's settling in,
it's like a magical mixture of cabbage worm, iron, and lemon.
Those are very different things, Laios.
It's pretty hard to describe it properly.
Are you sure it's okay to be eating magical creatures?
You'll hear things and get nosebleeds again.
What are those hallucinations?
Hmm.
When we make it back, you should see a doctor.
Or a shrink.
Why?
Do you think this is some kind of illness?
Wait, is this a hallucination, too?
Can you guys see this thing?
Yeah, I can see it.
Hey, uh, not to interrupt.
But we're under attack here!
Ew.
What are you wearing?
Is it the skin of a frog?
You know, I think the horns on this one's helmet
are just for decoration.
A child, huh?
They could be demons in disguise.
Shall we discover their true nature?
How about we kill one and see if...
Mizaru, that's enough.
I know them.
Shuro!
It's so good to see you!
It's been a while!
I never thought we'd meet in a situation like this!
What a sprawl world!
Did you lose weight?
I appreciate it, Shuro.
I'm relieved to see you're doing well, buddy.
How overly familiar!
Oh, yeah!
Before I forget.
First up, Senshi.
This is Shuro.
He used to be a member of our party.
Who is this Shuro?
One of the best fighters I've ever seen.
Is he referring to Lord Toshiro?
Not to mention he's about the only person who'd call me a friend.
Toshiro!
That's enough standing.
Come sit with us.
You caught us while we were eating.
You and your friend should...
That's quite the large group you have.
Hey, Kabru.
Kabru, aren't they?
Nice to meet you.
I believe your name is Laios, right?
Yeah.
Nice to meet you.
I wonder just how long it's been.
Hey, Kabru.
Hmm?
It's them, isn't it?
They're the ones who stole our things.
What do we do?
Hmm.
We don't do anything.
Huh?
Then why did we bother coming all this way?
Hmm.
I wanted to meet him in person.
Huh?
I doubt there's any point in asking about the jewels.
There wasn't any guilt on his face when he saw us.
So either he forgot, we blamed the wrong people,
the jewels themselves were a trap from the beginning,
or all of the above.
Did we come here for nothing?
Not at all.
Give me more time to observe.
Aren't you curious about how their party got this far?
Or what they might be planning to do next?
Because I am.
So, I'm assuming you guys have been on this floor for a while now, huh?
That's right.
We've been going in circles trying to get out,
but we keep getting turned around.
We got pretty lost in this place, too.
Lucky for us, Chilchuk discovered a pattern to the changes,
and that's how we managed to make it this far.
That's so.
This is unrelated, but...
Wow, Cheryl.
You're more depraved than I thought.
Are they your other plans?
You've been busy, huh?
They're merely family,
but they're skilled at fighting.
I'm sorry I left the party.
You see, once I realized she wasn't on the surface,
I did what I thought would be the best way
for me to get back into the dungeon,
so I could start searching for her.
My apologies.
It's fine.
We understand.
Although, I'm surprised that you went back in immediately.
Don't you think that was a bit rash?
What if somebody were to get hurt again?
It must have crossed your mind.
Well, for your information,
the four of us were able to defeat the Red Dragon.
Wait, the Red Dragon?
And where... where is...
Cheryl!
My lord!
My lord, I'm begging you,
please eat a meal and get proper sleep.
At this rate, your body will not last long.
You've been pushing yourself that hard?
Elias, anyone with eyes can see that he's not doing well.
Eating a good meal and getting rest is really important.
I have no time for such things.
Cheryl, you shouldn't just eat food when you have the time.
To have the energy to do what you want to do,
you need to eat and sleep when your body tells you that you need it.
Let's eat something.
While we do, I can fill you in on what's happened.
All right, then.
Can you prepare a meal for us, Maizaru?
It's mealtime!
Let us begin preparing!
Tade, you go fetch some water.
Okay.
Hien, Benichidori, you two start preparing the rice.
And Ausebi, your job is...
To protect our lord from harm.
Can't have you adding strange things to the food.
I'll go start lighting a fire for you all.
Oh my, so thoughtful.
I'll leave that to you then, Dwarf.
Food time, yummy, but...
There sure are a lot of people here.
It's not good to have this many people all in one place.
We should split into three groups.
Hmm.
Very well.
Oren!
Huh?
Dwarf!
Frog girl!
Frog!
If you're capable of magic, then provide us with a barrier.
It's to prevent monsters from disturbing our lord's meal.
Well, pleasure to meet you, Miss Frog.
Oh.
Same.
All right.
Let's step away from the group.
Ben will tell you everything we've been up to.
Let me help.
Thanks.
Thanks so much, James.
So what I'll tell you.
In this situation, I think the person in the most danger is...
Monsters are yummy.
They're the best!
Monsters cooking food.
Yum, yum.
Eat a lot.
I'll kill you.
Senshi!
I'll come out for the fire!
Hey, aren't you overdoing it a little bit?
So much smoke.
They must have him take a bath after his meal.
Here?
Why don't you have a seat right over there?
Fine.
Now hurry and tell me what's happened.
Well, after you and Namari left the group, the rest of us...
Stick to the main points.
We defeated the Red Dragon, then retrieved Falon and brought her back to life.
But then we were attacked by the Mad Mage, and we got separated.
We decided that we couldn't do this on our own, so we were going back to the surface to ask around for some help.
But we got lost.
You see?
That's why I'm glad we ran into you!
Please, lend us your strength, Shuro!
Mind if I ask a few questions?
The one who created this place is the Mad Mage you mentioned just now, is that correct?
There's only been rumors of his existence, and whoever actually saw him never returned.
How'd you know it was the Mad Mage you saw?
Well, I guess I thought he talked like he fit the part.
And how'd you manage to get away from that dangerous situation?
That was all Marcille.
Oh, she's our magic user, and she held him off.
Can you elaborate?
Well, uh...
Magic isn't really my thing, so I couldn't say.
Oh, I see.
May I ask something too, Lyos?
Hmm?
Did I see you eating a brick earlier?
No!
Ah, no, no, no!
It wasn't a brick.
We were eating part of a wall that was made of dungeon cleaners.
We left almost everything behind, including food and money, remember?
So for us to traverse the dungeon faster, we've been eating monsters this entire time!
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha
That's...
Hmm?
That's actually really interesting.
Well, what's the most delicious thing you've had so far?
Man, I don't know.
That's a hard one.
Kelpie, Living Armour.
You know, it might be the red dragon.
No way!
You ate the red dragon that ate your sister?
Yeah.
You said living armor.
What's even edible on it?
That's an excellent question.
It's actually a mollusk creature that uses the armor as a shell,
just like this sword.
Whoa!
The cleaners are eating Kensuke!
Can't be too careful.
By the way, if you're interested in monster meals,
we can talk about it whenever.
Wow, I appreciate that.
Oh, no.
He's actually serious about this.
Anyway, you had mentioned that you had resurrected Fallon.
Was she safe the last time you saw her?
Uh, yeah.
Do you know where she might be?
There are many places where you can hide on this floor,
but most of them are in orcs' territory.
Oh, yeah.
The orcs shouldn't be an issue.
Oh?
What'd they taste like?
We didn't eat them.
There were some things that happened,
and now we're in a cooperative relationship.
Mm-hmm.
Co-operative relationship?
Technically, it's an adventurous duty to kill any orcs.
Regarding where she is,
it's possible she's on a much deeper floor of the dungeon.
The one who kidnapped her may have taken her there.
Wait, kidnapped?
But why her?
Uh, well...
I think telling Shuro would be fine.
Sorry, but could I talk with him privately?
Sure.
That's not a problem at all.
So?
It's not that field ration pellets are bad,
but having them every day,
I just think you need to have something warm in your belly from time to time.
Cheers to that.
Meals should do a lot more than fill your stomach
until the next chance you get to eat.
You know, you're quite sensible for a dwarf.
Our lord's been sickly ever since childhood.
His appetite was lacking,
and it made everyone around him worry.
However, no matter the situation,
he would always eat the food I prepared for him.
Sometimes I'd be summoned to the kitchen in the middle of an assignment.
He was such an obedient child growing up
that it made me anxious.
The only selfish request he's ever made
was the one that brought us here.
Please, Maizuru.
There's someone that I wish to save.
Lend me your strength.
Oh.
To think some northern girl would steal his heart
during his training journey.
What can I even say to dissuade him?
You really want him to give up?
The head of the family bestowed me
with the task of looking after the young lord,
so I cannot act based on emotion.
In that case,
then what do you think you're doing right now?
If you have preserved foods,
there's no need to go through the trouble
of preparing a fresh meal.
Hmm?
Why do you reckon he ate up
all the things you personally made for him?
Maybe you didn't realize at the time,
but I know what you put in there.
A little ingredient called love.
What are you saying?
Are you proud of yourself for that one?
Although, at this point,
I just might give in.
So, depending on how things turn out,
perhaps I'll put in a good word for those, too.
Why did the art style change so much?
This depiction might be a bit of a stretch,
don't you think?
Yes.
This will suffice.
It's ready!
Hurry, dwarf!
It's important we have my lord eat this
while it's still warm!
Oh?
You two.
Why are you outside?
They said they wanted to speak in private.
My lord, I'm coming in.
My lord!
What is going on?
Did this man do something?
Tell me!
I need to know what happened here!
Sorry, but we couldn't hear from there.
It's black magic.
This man and the others
used black magic and monster flesh
to revive the northern girl.
What?
How could you do such a thing?
Do you even know what you have done?
People who deal with black magic,
the reasons that they have matter not.
They are nothing but criminals!
They get locked in dark cells until they die,
and their corpses are never returned.
If the western elves find out,
then who knows what they'll do to her?
That's assuming this leaves the dungeon, Shuro.
And you won't tell another soul
about any of this happening.
Right?
We had no other options.
Please understand.
Black magic.
This is crazier than I imagined.
How's this gonna turn out?
I must locate you as soon as possible.